<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>CodeShard</title><link href="http://codeshard.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://codeshard.github.io/feeds/articles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://codeshard.github.io/</id><updated>2014-03-24T01:46:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Pelican-Trapped: My own pelican theme</title><link href="http://codeshard.github.io/pelican-trapped-my-own-pelican-theme.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-24T01:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ozkar L. Garcell</name></author><id>tag:codeshard.github.io,2014-03-24:pelican-trapped-my-own-pelican-theme.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I decided make my own blog on github, I made a research about all static site generators available. My first choice was Octopress, but I don't speak Ruby yet, so Pelican was introduced to myself by my friend &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://xr09.github.io/"&gt;XR09&lt;/a&gt;. Written in Python, command line, RST and MarkDown, it was difficult not falling inlove with Pelican. Then come other problem: choose a minimalistic theme that fit with my character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I see Octopress default theme, I choose it without hesitate, because is very simple and readable. But XR09 was a step forward :(. So I decided make my own pelican theme, and here is it! Inspired on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes"&gt;pelican-bootstrap3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes"&gt;simple-bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, and some other ideas I saw around the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/codeshard/pelican-trapped"&gt;fork&lt;/a&gt; the repository and send a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="articles"></category><category term="programming"></category><category term="ideas"></category></entry><entry><title>The web must be simple and focused</title><link href="http://codeshard.github.io/the-web-must-be-simple-and-focused.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-21T19:15:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ozkar L. Garcell</name></author><id>tag:codeshard.github.io,2014-03-21:the-web-must-be-simple-and-focused.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The web: a tool for human beings. A human being who is fullfilling a task(send and email, reading news, buy a book, watch a movie). And as a tool, must be usable, must be easy and fluid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, if this tool turns difficult? If this human being feels &lt;em&gt;pain&lt;/em&gt; when browsing the web? If this tool, more than a pleasure became in a torture?
Sometimes we feel that way, when we go to a particular web and every link hurts like a thorn, every color make our eyes bleed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usability of a web has been misunderstood by many web developers and designers when they forget that the users browse the web(even if a personal blog) looking for something, and the users in some specific cases could feel lost and disappointed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The users rulz the web! This means: without users your web site dies, so, take care of it and fulfill your users wishes. The users love a web faster than pretty, secure tahn modern, simple than complex, so, be smart and gather all this requirements!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't waste your users time! Adds, dancing clips, useless links, anything but consistence could bother!
When you gain your users trust, take care of it, the abyss is one click away!
Just simplify, reduce and optimize!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="articles"></category><category term="web desing"></category><category term="web development"></category></entry></feed>